ILGWU Operations Department Collective Bargaining Agreements 5780/202
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
ILGWU Operations Department Collective Bargaining Agreements
1988-1998
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union
5780/202
1 cubic feet
1 linear ft.
Records (documents).
This collection includes records from both the Research Department and the Operations Department. Arranged alphabetically by company, these records consist of collective bargaining agreements negotiated by local unions of the ILGWU and various companies.
6766330
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, May 18, 2011
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, April 16, 2019
Biographical / Historical
The International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union was once one of the largest labor unions in the United States founded in 1900 by local union delegates representing about 2,000 members in cities in the northeastern United States. It was one of the first U.S. Unions to have a membership consisting of mostly females, and it played a key role in the labor history of the 1920s and 1930s. The union is generally referred to as the "ILGWU" or the "ILG". The ILGWU grew in geographical scope, membership size, and political influence to become one of the most powerful forces in American organized labor by mid-century. Representing workers in the women's garment industry, the ILGWU worked to improve working and living conditions of its members through collective bargaining agreements, training programs, health care facilities, cooperative housing, educational opportunities, and other efforts. The ILGWU merged with the Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union in 1995 to form the Union of Needle trades, Industrial and Textile Employees (UNITE). UNITE merged with the Hotel Employees and Restaurant Employees Union (HERE) in 2004 to create a new union known as UNITE HERE. The two unions that formed UNITE in 1995 represented only 250,000 workers between them, down from the ILGWU's peak membership of 450,000 in 1969.
Biographical / Historical
Little documentation exists in the ILGWU records about the work of the Operations Department in the union's international offices, and the materials that comprise the Operations Department records do not explicitly show that they were created by the department per se. While typically an operations department is known to deal with the everyday business of an organization and to have responsibility for the organization's facilities, the records suggest that the department either complemented the work of the Research Department, the Master Agreements Department, and the former Management Engineering Department, or maintained records useful to those departments.
Scope and Contents
The Operations Department records consist of materials relating to the ILGWU's efforts to maintain a ban on industrial homework, manuals for operations standards in the manufacturing of women's blouses and women's skirts, and collective bargaining agreements. The records relating to homework and operations standards date from the 1980s, and the collective bargaining agreements are from the years just before the ILGWU merged with ACTWU in 1995.
Researchers interested in ILGWU statements on homework and related issues should consult the Research Department records, 5780/209. Likewise, researchers looking for additional collective bargaining agreements should consult collections in Series VI, Contracts and Case Files (5780/075, 5780/075 mf, 5780/145, 5780/146, 5780/147, 5780/158, 5780/191). These records, and others throughout the ILGWU records, complement the records of the Operations Department.
This collection includes the collective bargaining agreements negotiated by local unions of the ILGWU and various companies.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5780: ILGWU records 5780/196: ILGWU Operations Department Industrial Homework Records 5780/202 PUBS: ILGWU Operations Department Publications Operations Standards Manuals
Collective bargaining--Clothing industry--New York (State)--New York; Collective bargaining--Textile industry--New York (State)--New York; Textile workers--Labor unions--New York (State)--New York; Clothing workers--Labor unions--New York (State)--New York; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union.; Accurate Lace Dye Experts, Inc.; Ajax Shoulder Pad Company, Inc.; Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union; American White Cross, Inc.; Bari Manufacturing Corporation; Biener and Son, Inc.; Brooks Brothers (Firm); Buster Brown Apparel, Inc.; California Ranchwear; Chase Packaging Corporation; Cleve-Tenn Industries, Inc.; Cliftex Corporation/Cutting Room; College House Manufacturing; Columbia Wool Scouring Mills; Cone Mills Corporation; Cooper Sportswear Manufacturing Company, Inc.; Country Miss, Inc.; Crown Yarn Dye Company, Inc.; Hallmark Emblems, Inc.; Harris-Tipograph, Inc.; Ideal Shoulder Pad Company; Imperial Coat Front Company, Inc.; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union. Operations Department.; Interstate Dyeing and Finishing Company; Kellwood Company; Lee County Manufacturing; Lehigh Valley Throwing Mills, Inc.; Levi Strauss and Company; Lilly Industrial Coatings; Meren Industries, Inc.; Mespo Umbrella Ltd.; Midlantic/New York Pad; Miller Brothers, Inc.; Missbrenner Prints, Inc.; Moderne Gloves, Inc.; Monroe Prints, Inc.; Montreal Fast Print, Ltd.; National Knitted Processors, Inc.; Oneita Industries, Inc.; Peerless Rug Ltd.; Perennial Print Corporation; Perfection Pad Company, Inc.; Poughkeepsie Finishing Corporation; Rainbow Dyeing and Finishing Company; River Warping, Inc.; Schertz Umbrellas, Inc.; Sierra Plastics, Inc.; Societe de la Broderie; Tavernon Photo Engraving Company; Techniplast, Inc.; Texas Apparel; Union of Needletrades, Industrial and Textile Employees; UNITE HERE (Organization); United Global Distributors, Inc.; Warwick Dying Corporation; Wimpfheimer A. and Brothers, Inc.; Windsor Textile Processing, Inc.; American White Cross, Inc.
6766330
- All Fashions Corporation. Local 148, 1991-1994 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Scope and Contents
  Union City, New Jersey
- Allied Underwear Association, Local 63-32, 1990-1996 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  NY, NY
- Ambow Corp, Local 162, 1994-1997 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Hoboken, NJ
- Angela Sports Limited, Local 33, 1994-1997 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Boston, MA
- Arlene Sports Company, Boston Joint Board, 1994-1997 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Aquilla Fashions Local 225, 1991-1994 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  Lansford, PA
- Betsy Flags Local 90, 1992-1994 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  Lake Bluff, IL
- Broderie Ritz Ltee Local 315, 1993-1998 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  Montreal, QU
- Canadian African Newcomer Aid Center Local 136, 1994-1996 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  Toronto, ON
- Cherrybill Manufacturing Local 277, 1991-1994 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  Tucson, AZ
- Copan's Enterprises Local 415, 1994-1997 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  Pompano Beach, FL
- Country Miss, 1988-1994 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Howard Korenstein Sportswear Local 166, 1994-1997 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  Newark, NJ
- JH Collectibles Local 188, 1994-1997 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  Milwaukee, WI
- J.K. Operating Company Local 185, 1995-1966 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  Kulpmont, PA
- Jayo Sportswear Company Local 234, 1993-1996 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  Bethlehem, PA
- Koret of California Local 215, 1993-1995 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  Napa, CA
- Koret of California Local 294, 1989-1992 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  Price, UT
- La Compagnie de Broderie Lippm, Quebec Joint Council, 1993-1996 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Liz Claiborne Shoes Local 130, 1994-1997 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  Dayton, NJ
- Lingerie Love'Lee Made Local 352, 1995-1996 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Maiden Mills Industries Local 281, 1994-1996 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  Lawrence, MA
- Manhattan Children's Wear, Quebec Joint Council, 1993-1998 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Pennsylvania Textile Corporation Local 225, 1993-1996 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  W. Hazleton
- Quality Garment Company Local 256, 1994-1997 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  West Union, WV
- Salon de Coiffure Forrest Local 208, 1993-1995 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Societe de la Broderie Canadienne Local 315, 1993-1996 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Seneca Knitting Mills Local 89-22-1, 1995-1998 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  Seneca Falls, NY
- Service America Corporation, 1994-1997 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  Evansville, IN
- Iranian Community Association of Ontario Local 136, 1995-1996 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  Downs view, ON
- United Knitwear Manufacturers' League Local 99, 1991-1994 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  New York, NY
- Urkov Manufacturing Local 76, 1992-1995 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  Chicago, IL